"Once upon a time there was a lovely princess
从前有一位可爱的公主
"But she had an enchantment upon her of a fearful sort...
但是她被可怕的魔法控制了
"which could only be broken by love's first kiss.
只有真爱的初吻才可以解除这魔法
"She was locked away in a castle...
她被困在一个城堡里
"guarded by a terrible fire-breathing dragon.
由一只喷火龙看守着
"Many brave knights had attempted to free her from this deadful prison.
有许多勇敢的骑士曾经想 把她从这可怕的监狱中救走
"but none prevailed.
但是  没有一个成功
"She waited in the dragon's keep...
她关在被喷火龙看守着的
"in the highest room of the tallest tower...
城堡里最高的房间里
for her true love and true love's first kiss. "
等待着真爱的初吻
Like that's ever gonna happen
那是不会发生的
《怪物史瑞克》
- Think it's in there? - All right. Let's get it!
- 我想它在里面  - 我们去吧!
Whoa, Hold on. Do you know what thing can do to you?
慢着!你知道会发生什么吗?
Yeah, it'll grind your bones for its bread.
它会把你的骨头当面包吃
Yes, well, actually, that would be a giant.
其实那是一个巨人
Now, ogres...  They're much worse.
不过  更糟糕的可能是个怪物
They'll make a suit from your freshly peeled skin.
它们会扒下你们新鲜的皮肤做汤
They'll shave your liver.
挖出你的心肝
Squeeze the jelly from your eyes!
用你的眼睛榨果汁
- Actualy, it's quite good on toast. - Back! Back, beast!
- 这样吃吐司面包味道会很好  - 退后  退后  怪物
Back! I warn ya!
我警告你
This is the part where you run away.
你们还不快走就没有机会了
And stay out!
滚吧!
"Wanted. Fairy tale creatures. "
通缉:童话人物
All right. This one's full
好的  这车满了
Take it away!
拉走
- Move it along. Come on! Get up! - Next!
- 走  快点  快点   - 下一个
Give me that! Your flying days are over.
给我  你飞行的日子要结束了
That's 20 pieces of silver for the witch. Next!
这是给你的20银币  下一个!
Get up! Come on!
起来  快点
Keep quiet!
安静点!
This cage is too small.
笼子太小了
Please don't turn me in. I'll never be stubborn again.
请不要让我进去  我不再顽固了
I can change. Please! Give ma another chance!
我会改的  再给我一次机会
Oh, shut up.
闭嘴
- Next! What have you got? - This little wooden puppet.
- 下一个  什么东西  - 这是一个小木偶
I'm not a puppet. I'm a real boy.
我不是木偶  我是一个真正的男孩
Five shillings forthe possessed toy.
5先令给你这个疯狂的玩具
Take it away.
拿走
Next. What have you got?
下一个  什么东西?
Well, I've got a talking donkey.
我有一头会说话的驴子
Right. Well, that's good for ten shillings, if you can prouve it.
好的  如果你能证明  我给你十先令
Oh, go ahead, little fella.
好的  说吧  伙计
Oh, oh, he's just...  He's just a little nervous.
哦  它只是有点紧张
He's really quite a chatterbox. Talk, you boneheaded dolt...
它可是个话匣子呀  说话啊!你这头蠢驴!
- That's it. I've heard enough. Guards! - No, no, he talks!
- 好了  我听够了  守卫! - 不  不  它能说话
He does. I can talk. I love to talk.
我能说话  我爱说话
I'm the talkingest damn thing you ever saw.
我是你见过的最能说话的驴子
- Get her out of my sight. - No, no!
- 把她带走   - 不  不要
I swear! Oh! He can talk!
我发誓  它能说话
Hey! I can fly!
嘿  我会飞!
- He can fly! - He can fly!
- 它会飞  - 会飞!
He can talk! Ha, ha! That's right, fool!
它说话了  对了  笨蛋
Now I'm a flying, talking donkey.
对  现在我是会飞会说话的驴子
Your right have seen a house fly maybe even a super fly,
你可能看过蝇子  而且是一个很大的蝇子
but I bet you ain't never seen a donkey fly.
不过你肯定没有看过会飞的驴子
Seize him!
抓住它
After him! He's getting away!
在这边  快过来
You there. Ogre!
是你  怪物
Aye?
什么事?
By the order of Lord Farquaad, I am authorized to place you under arrest...
奉弗瓜王之命  授权我逮捕你们两个
and transport you to a designated... resettlement facility.
送到一个指定地...
Oh, really? You and what army?
是吗?你和什么军队?
Can I say something to you?
我可以跟你说话吗?
Listen, you was really, really somethin' back there. Incredible!
听着  你的确有些本领  了不起!
Are you talking to... me? Whoa!
你在跟我说话吗?
Yes, I was talkin' to you. Can I tell you that you was great back there? Those guards!
是的  我在跟你说话  你刚才真的很厉害
They thought they was all of that. Then you showed up, and bam!
那些侍卫以为自己很棒  然后你一出现  砰!
They was trippin' over themselves like babes in the woods.
都跑光了
That really made me feel good to see that.
我看了感觉很爽
- Oh, that's great. Really. - Man, it's good to be free.
- 很棒  真的   - 获得自由的感觉真好
Now, why don't you go celebrate your freedom with your own friends? Hmm?
去跟你的朋友庆祝你的自由吧
But, uh, I don't have any friends.
可是我没有朋友
And I'm not goin' out there by myself.
我也不会单独出去
Hey, wait a minute! I got a great idea! I'll stick with you.
嘿  等等  我有一个很好的建议  我跟着你好吗
You're a mean, green, fightin' machine.
你是一个令人恐惧的绿色怪物
Together we'll scare the spit out of anybody that crosses us.
遇到我们的人会被我们一起吓跑
Oh, wow! That was really scary.
噢  真吓人
If you don't mind me sayin' if that don't work, your breath certainly will get the job done,
这很可怕  如果不管用  你呼口气就可以了
'cause you definitely need some Tic Tacs or something, 'cause your breath stinks!
你需要些口香糖  你有点口臭
You almost burned the hair outta my nose,
你几乎把我的鼻毛都烧着了
just like the time...
就像那次...
Then I ate some rotten berries. I had strong gases eking out of my butt that day.
...我吃了一些烂草莓后放了很多屁
Why are you following me?
你为什么跟着我?
I'll tell you why.
我告诉你原因
'Cause I'm all alone
因为我寂寞
There's no one here beside me
没有人陪我
My problems have all gone
我的烦恼都走开
There's no one to deride me
没有人会嘲笑我
But you gotta have friend...
当你有了朋友...
Stop singing!
别唱了!
It's no wonder you don't have any friends.
怪不得你没有朋友
Wow. Only a true friend would be that truly honest.
噢  只有真正的朋友才会这么诚实
Listen, little donkey. Take a look at me. What am I?
听着  驴子  看看我  我是什么?
- Really tall? - No! I'm an ogre.
- 真高?  - 不!我是个怪物
You know. "Grab your torch and pitchforks. "
想像一下:拿着你的火把和草杈!
Doesn't that bother you?
这不让你烦恼吗?
Nope.
不
- Really? - Really,really.
- 真的?  - 真的  真的
Man, I like you. What's your name?
我喜欢你  你叫什么?
Uh, Shrek.
史莱克
Shrek? Well, you know what I like about you, Shrek?
史莱克?知道我喜欢你什么?
You got a kind of I don't care what nobody thinks of me thing.
你不在乎别人怎么看自己
I like that. I respect that, Shrek. You alright.
我喜欢这个  我敬佩这个  史莱克
Whoo! Look at that. Who'd want to live in a place like that?
瞧那边!谁住在那里?
That would be my home.
那是我的家
Oh! And it is lovely! Just beautiful.
很好!太漂亮了!
You are quite a decorator. It's amazing what you've done with such a modest budget.
你是个相当不错的装饰设计家 在预算有限的情况下  你所做的令人惊叹!
I like that boulder. That is a nice boulder.
我喜欢那块石头  很漂亮
I guess you don't entertain much, do you?
我猜想你家里不常来客人
I like my privacy.
我喜欢一个人呆着
You know, I do too. That's another thing we have in comon.
我也是这样  这是我们的另一个共同点
Like, I hate it when you got somebody in your face.
我讨厌有人来
You're trying to give them a hint, and they won't leave. There's that awkward silence.
来了就不肯走  尴尬的沉默
- Can I stay with you? - Uh, what?
- 我跟你住可以吗?  - 什么?
Can I stay with you, please?
让我跟你一起住  好吗?
- Of course! - Really?
- 当然!  - 真的?
- No. - Please! I don't wanna go back there!
- 不!  - 我不想回去!
You don't know what it's like to be considered a freak. Well, maybe you do.
你知道被当作怪物的感受
But that's why we gotta stick together. You gotta let me stay!
这就是为什么我们要在一起  让我留下吧!
- Please! Please! - Okay! Okay!
- 求求你!  - 好吧
- But one night only. - Ah! Thank you!
- 但你只能呆一晚上  - 谢谢!
- What are you... No! No! - This is gonna be fun!
- 你干什么... 不! 不! - 这将会很有趣!
We can stay up late, swappin' manly stories,
我们晚点儿睡  一起讲故事
and in the mornin' I'm makin' waffles.
早上我做薄饼
Where do, uh, I sleep?
我在哪里睡?
Outside!
外面!
Oh,well, I guess that's cool.
哇  那很酷
I mean, I don't know you, and you don't know me,
我的意思是我不了解你  你也不了解我
so I guess outside is best, you know.
因此我想外头最好
Here I go.
我出去了
Good night.
晚安
I mean, I do like the outdoors. I'm a donkey. I was born outside.
我确实喜欢在外面  我是驴  生来就喜欢外面
I'll just be sitting by myself outside, I guess, you know.
只有我一个人在外面
By myself, outside.
一个人  在外面
I'm all alone. There's no one here beside me
只有我一个人  这里除了我没有别人
I thought I told you to stay outside.
我不是告诉你呆在外头吗?
I am outside.
我是在外头
Well, gents, it's a far cry from the farm, but what choice do we have?
这比农场差远了  不过还有什么办法呢?
It's not home, but it'll do just fine.
这不是家  但还算不错
What a lovely bed.
多好的床
- Got ya. - I found some cheese.
- 抓到你了　 - 我找到了些奶酪
Blah! Awful stuff.
真恶心!
- Is that you, Gorder? - How did you know?
- 是你吗  戈德?  - 你怎么知道是我?
Enough! What are you doing in my house?
够了!你在我的房子里干嘛?
Oh!, no, no, no.
不  不  不!
- Dead broad off the table. - Where are we supposed to put her? The bed's taken.
- 死人不能放在桌子上  - 可床已经被占了!
What?
什么?
I live in a swamp. I put up signs. I'm a terrifying ogre!
我住在沼泽地里  我贴出告示 我是个可怕的怪物!
What do I have to do to get a little privacy?
我怎么才能保留点隐私呢?
- Aah! - Oh, no.
- 啊!  - 不
Oh, no.
哦  不
No! No!
不...不!
What are you doing in my swamp?
你们在我的沼泽地里干什么?
All right, get out of here. All of you, move it!
好  出去  你们都离开这里  走开!
Come on! Let's go! Quickly. Come on!
快点儿  快!
No, no!
不
No, no. Not there. Not there.
不是那里  不是那里
Hey, don't look at me. I didn't invite them.
别看我  不是我请他们来的
Oh, gosh, no one invited us.
没人请我们来
- What? - We were forced to come here.
- 什么?  - 我们被迫来到这里
- By who? - Lord Farquaad.
- 谁强迫你们?  - 弗瓜王
He huffed und he puffed und he... signed an eviction notice.
他把我们赶走
Who knows where this Farquaad guy is?
谁知道弗瓜王在哪里?
Oh, I do. I know where he is.
我知道
Does anyone else know where to find him?
还有人知道在哪里能找到他吗?
- Anyone at all? - Me! Me!
- 没人知道?  - 我知道!
- Anyone? - Oh! Oh, pick me!
- 谁知道?  - 选我!
Oh, I know! I know! Me, me!
我知道!我知道!我!
Okay, fine.
好
Attention, all fairy tale things.
注意  你们这些童话人物
Do not get comfortable. Your welcome is officially worn out.
别再享受了  欢迎已经正式结束了
In fact, I'm gonna see this guy Farquaad right now...
实际上  我马上就要去见弗瓜王这个家伙
and get you all off my land and back where you came from!
把你们从我这里弄走  回你们老家!
Oh! You!
你!
You're comin' with me.
你跟我来
All right, that's what I like to hear, man
这正是我喜欢听到的
Shrek and donkey, two stalwart friends, off on a whirlwind big-city adventure.
史莱克和驴  两个朋友一起去冒险
I love it!
我喜欢
On the road again
又上路了  史莱克  跟我一起唱
I can't wait to get on the road again
我迫不及待要上路了...
What did I say about singing?
关于唱歌我刚才说什么了?
- Can I whistle? - No.
- 我可以吹口哨儿吗?   - 不
- Can I hum it? - All right, hum it.
- 可以哼歌吗?  - 好吧  哼吧
That's enough. He's ready to talk.
够了  他要开口了
Run, run, run, as fast as you can.
跑  跑  赶快跑
You can't catch me. I'm the gingerbread man!
你抓不到我  我是个姜饼人!
- You're a monster. - I'm not the monster here. You are.
- 你是魔鬼  - 我不是  你才是
You and the rest of that fairy tale trash, poisoning my perfect world.
你和其他的童话垃圾毒害了我完美的世界
Now, tell me! Where are the others?
告诉我  他们都到哪里去了?
Eat me!
吃我!
I've tried to be fair to you creatures.
我试着公平地对待你们这些东西
Now my patience has reached its end! Tell me or I'll...
现在  我的耐心消失了! 告诉我  不然...
No, no, not the buttons. Not my gumdrop buttons.
不  别动我的糖浆扣子!
All right then. Who's hiding them?
谁把他们藏起来了?
Okay, I'll tell you. Do you know the muffin man?
好  我告诉你  你知道松饼人吗?
- The muffin man? - The muffin man.
- 松饼人?   - 松饼人
Yes, I know the muffin man, who lives on Drury Lane?
对  我知道松饼人  她住在特鲁里街?
Well, she's married to the muffin man.
她跟松饼人结婚了
- The muffin man? - The muffin man!
- 松饼人?  - 松饼人!
She's married to the muffin man.
她跟松饼人结婚了
My lord! We found it.
主人!我们找到了!
Then what are you waiting for? Bring it in.
你还等什么?把它带进来
- Magic mirror...  - Don't tell him anything!
- 魔镜...    - 什么都不要告诉他!
No!
不要!
Evening.
晚上好
Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
魔镜啊魔镜
Is this not the most perfect kingdom of them all?
这不是最完美的王国吗?
Well, technically you're not a king.
严格地讲你不是国王
- You were saying? - What I mean is, you're not a king yet.
- 你说什么?  - 我意思是...你还不是国王
But you can become one. All you have to do is marry a princess.
但你可以成为国王  只要娶个公主就行了
Go on.
接着说
So, just sit back and relax, my lord,
那么  放松点坐下吧  主人
because it's time for you to meet today's eligible bachelorettes.
你就要会见当今最合格的未婚女子了
And here they are!
她们来了!
Bachelorette number one is a mentally abused shut-in from a kingdom far, far away.
一号来自遥远的王国  精神上倍受折磨
She likes sushi and hot tubbing anytime.
她喜欢吃寿司和洗热水澡
Her hobbies include cooking and cleaning for her two evil sisters.
她还要为她的两个坏姐姐做饭和打扫卫生
Please welcome Cinderella.
欢迎灰姑娘!
Bachelorette number two is a cape-wearing girl from the land of fancy.
二号是位身穿斗篷的姑娘  她来自奇幻之地
Although she lives with seven other men, she's not easy.
她与七个男人一起生活  她很不简单
Just kiss her dead, frozen lips and find out what a live wire she is.
亲吻她冰凉的嘴唇   看看她火热的激情吧
Come on. Give it up for Snow White!
快来为白雪公主鼓掌吧!
And last, but certainly not least,
最后一位  但不是最差的
bachelorette number three is a fiery redhead...
一位红发姑娘来自被龙看守的
from a dragon-guarded castle surrounded by hot boiling lava!
火山岩浆围绕的城堡
But don't let that cool you off.
但别因此而灰心
Yours for the rescuing, Princess Fiona!
渴望被拯救的菲奥纳公主
So will it be bachelorette number one,
是一号?
bachelorette number two or bachelorette number three?
二号还是三号?
- Two! Two! - Three! Three!
- 二号!三号!  - 三号!
- Two! Two! - Three!
Three? One? Three?
三号?一号?三号?
Three! Pick number three, my lord!
选三号  主人!
Okay, okay, uh, number three!
好  好  三号!
Lord Farquaad, you've chosen Princess Fiona.
弗瓜王  你选了菲奥纳公主
Princess Fiona.
菲奥纳公主
She is perfect.
她是完美的
All I have to do is just find someone who can go...
我只想找一个能去...
But I probably should mention the little thing that happens at night.
我应该说一下发生在晚上的事...
- I'll do it. - Yes, but after sunset...
- 我会跟她结婚的  - 可是日落后...
Silence! I will make this Princess Fiona my queen,
安静!我要菲奥纳公主做我的王后
and DuLoc will finally have the perfect king!
杜洛克将会有一个十全十美的国王
Captain, assemble your finet men.
队长  召集你最优秀的部下
We're going to have a tournament.
我们要举行一场比赛
But that's it. That'st it right there. That's DuLoc.
就是那里  那就是杜洛克
I told ya I'd find it.
我说过我会找到的
So, that must be Lord Farquaad's castle.
那么  那一定是弗瓜王的城堡了
Uh...huh. That's the place.
就是那里
Do you think maybe he's compensating for something?
你看他是不是在弥补什么?
Hey, wait. Wait up, Shrek.
等等!等一下  史莱克
Hurry, darling. We're late. Hurry.
快点儿  宝贝儿  我们晚了
Wait a second. Look, I'm not gonna eat ya.
等等  我不会吃掉你的
I just...  I just...
我只是...我只是...
It's quiet.
很安静
Too quiet.
太安静了
- WHere is everybody? - Hey, look at this!
- 人都到哪去了?  - 你看看这个!
Welcome to DuLoc such a perfect town
欢迎来杜洛克这个美丽的地方
Here we have some rules Let us lay them down
有一些规则要和你分享
Don't make waves, stay inline and we'll get along fine
要安静守秩序才会有好环境
DuLoc is a perfect place
杜洛克是个好地方
Please keep off of the grass Shine your shoes, wipe your... face
要爱护花和树  擦亮鞋  擦净...脸
DuLoc is, DuLoc is
杜洛克是  杜洛克是
DuLoc is a perfect
杜洛克是个好...
Place
地方
Wow! Let's do that again!
我们再来一遍!
No. No. No, no, no! No.
不  不  不  不!
Brave knights.
勇敢的骑士们
You are the best and brightest in the land.
你们是世界上最优秀  最聪明的人
Today one of you shall prove himself...
今天  你们中的一个将证明...
All right. You're going the right way for a smacked bottom.
你想挨巴掌吗?
Sorry about that.
对不起
That champion shall have the honour... no,no... the privilege...
冠军将得到荣誉...不...特权
to go forth and rescue the lovely Princess Fiona...
去救出可爱的菲奥纳公主
from the fiery keep of the dragon
从火龙严密的看守中
If for any reason the winner is unsuccessful,
如果因为意外冠军没有成功
the fist runner-up will take his place
亚军将代替他...
and so on and so forth.
以此类推
Some of you may die, but it's a sacrifice I am willing to make.
你们有些人可能会牺牲  但这是自愿的
Let the tournament begin!
比赛现在开始!
What is that?
那是什么?
- It's hideous! - Ah, that's not very nice.
- 丑的吓人!  - 这不是很漂亮
It's just a donkey. Huh?
不过是头驴而已
Indeed. Knights, new plan!
骑士们  新计划!
The one who kills the ogre will be named champion! Have at him!
杀死那个怪物的人将被授予冠军!进攻!
- Get him! - Oh, hey! Now come on! Hang on now.
- 抓住他!  - 嘿  现在  赶快!等等...
Go ahead! Get him!
去!抓住他!
Can't we just settle this over a pint?
我们可以友好的解决吗?
Kill the beast!
杀了这个怪物!
No? All right then.
不?那么  好吧
Come on!
来吧!
Hey, Shrek, tag me! Tag me!
嘿  史莱克  让我来!让我来!
The chair! Give him the chair!
给他椅子!
Thank you! Thank you very much!
谢谢!非常感谢!
I'm here till Thursday. Try the veal! Ha, ha!
我在这里呆到周四  尝尝牛排!哈哈
Shall I give the order, sir?
我可以下令吗  主人?
No, I have a better idea.
不  我有个更好的主意
People of DuLoc, I give you our champion!
杜洛克的人们  他就是我们的冠军!
- What? - Congratulations, ogre.
- 什么?　- 祝贺你  怪物
You've won the honour of embarking on a great and noble quest.
你赢得了一个伟大  高尚任务的荣誉
Quest? I'm already on a quest, a quest to get my swamp back.
任务?我的任务就是要归还我的沼泽地
- Your swamp? - Yeah, my swamp!
- 你的沼泽地?  - 对  我的沼泽地!
Where you dumped those fairy tale creatures!
你把那些童话人物丢弃到那里!
All right, ogre, I'll make you a deal.
好吧  怪物  我们做个交易
Go on this quest for me, and I'll give you your swamp back.
你为我完成任务  我就把沼泽地还给你
Exactly the way it was?
恢复原状?
Down to the last slime-covered toadtool.
跟原来一模一样
- And the squatters? - As good as gone.
- 那些不速之客呢?  - 全都弄走
What kind of quest?
什么样的任务?
Let me get this straight. You're gonna go fight a dragon...
你要去跟龙作战
and rescue a princess just so Farquaad will give you back a swamp...
救出公主  然后弗瓜王把沼泽地还给你
which you only don't have because he filled it full of freaks in the first place. Is that about right?
你的沼泽地现在被弗瓜王塞满了怪物  对吗?
Maybe there's a good reason donkeys shouldn't talk.
也许驴不能讲话是有道理的
I don't get it. Why don't you just pull some of that ogre stuff on him?
你为什么不把你的魔力都用在他身上?
Throttle him, lay siege to his fortress,
包围他的堡垒
grind his bones to make your bread, the whole ogre trip.
碾碎他们的骨头夹面包吃  怪物所有的本事
Oh, I know what.
我知道
Maybe I could have decapitated an entire village...
也许我可以砍掉全村人的头
and put thier heads on a pike,
把他们的头挂在长矛上
gotten a knife, cut open thier spleen and drink their fluids.
拿刀割开他们的肚子  喝他们的血
Does that sound good to you?
你看怎么样?
Uh, no, not really, no.
不  真的  不怎么样
For your information, there's a lot more to ogres than people think.
告诉你  怪物比你想像的复杂
- Example? - Example?
- 举个例子　 - 例子?
- Okay, um, ogres are like onions. - They stink?
- 好...怪物就像洋葱  - 有臭味?
- Yes  No! - They make you cry? - No!
- 不  - 让你流泪?  - 不!
You leave them out in the sun, they get all brown, start sproutin' little white hairs.
把它们放在阳光下晒成棕色  会长出嫩芽?
No! Layers!
是层!
Onions have layers.
洋葱有很多层
Ogres have layers! Onions have layers.
怪物有层  洋葱也有层
You gt it? We both have layers.
你明白吗?我们都有好多层
Oh, you both have layers. Oh.
你们都有好多层
You know, not everybody likes onions.
可并不是人人都喜欢洋葱
Cake! Everybody loves cakes! Cakes have layers.
蛋糕!大家都喜欢蛋糕!蛋糕也有层
I don't care... what everyone likes.
我不在乎...大家喜欢什么
Ogres are not like cakes.
怪物不像蛋糕
You know what else everybody likes? Parfaits.
你知道大家还喜欢什么?冰淇淋
Have you ever met a person, you, say, "Let's get some parfait,"
你试过问别人:吃冰淇淋吗?
they say, "No, I don't like no parfait"?
他回答 “不  我不喜欢冰淇淋”
- Parfaits are delicious. - No!
- 冰淇淋很好吃  - 没有!
You dense, irritating, miniature beast of burden!
你这个愚蠢讨厌的驴
Ogres are like onions! End of the story.
怪物像洋葱!行了吧
Bye-bye. See ya later.
再见  回头见
Parfaits may be the most delicious thing on the whole damn planet.
冰淇淋也许是这个世界上最美味的东西
You know, I think I preferred your humming.
我想我宁愿听你哼歌
Do you have a tissue or something? I'm making a mess.
你有纸巾吗?
Just the word parfait make me start slobbering.
提起冰淇淋让我流口水了
Ooh! Shrek! Did you do that?
史莱克!是你干的吗?
You gotta warn somebody before you just crack one off. My mouth was open.
你放屁之前得通知一声
Believe me, Donkey, if it was me, you'd be dead.
相信我  小驴  如果是我  你早就薰死了
It's brimstone.
是硫磺
- We must be getting close. - Yeah, right, brimstone.
- 我们一定快到了  - 对  硫磺...
Don't be talking about it's the brimstone. I know what I smell. It's wasn't no brimstone.
别告诉我硫磺  我知道我闻到了什么  不可能是硫磺
It didn't come off no stone neither.
也没有什么石头
Sure, it's big enough, but look at the location.
确实  这地方够大的  看看这周围
Uh, Shrek? Uh, remember when you said ogres have layers?
史莱克?记得你说过怪物有好多层吗?
Oh, aye.
没错
Well, I have a bit of a confession to make.
我有点儿事要坦白
Donkeys don't have layers. We wear our fear right out there on our sleeves.
驴没有好多层  我们的恐惧都表现在袖子上
- Wait a second. Donkeys don't have sleeves. - You know what I mean.
- 等等!驴没有袖子  - 你明白我的意思
You can't tell me you're afraid of heights.
你不要对我说你有恐高症
I'm just a little uncomfortable about being on a rickely bridge over a boiling lake of lava!
走在沸腾岩浆上面的桥上  我有点不舒服
Come on, Donkey. I'm right here beside ya, okay?
别怕  小驴  我就在你旁边
For emotional support,
鼓励你
we'll just tackle this thing together one little baby stap at a time.
我们一起走  一次只迈一小步
- Really? - Really, really.
- 真的?  - 真的  真的
- Okay, that makes me feel so much better. - Just keep moving.
- 这样我感觉好多了  - 继续走
- And don't look down. - Okay, don't look down. Don't look down.
- 别往下看...   - 继续走  别往下看
Don't look down. Keep on moving. Don't look down.
别往下看  向前走  别往下看
Shrek! I'm lookin' down!
史莱克!我在往下看!
Oh, God, I can't do this! Just let me off, please!
我过不去了!请放了我吧!
- But you're already halfway. - But I know that half is safe!
- 你已经走了一半了!  - 我知道那部分安全!
Okay, fine. I don't have time for this. You go back.
好  我没有时间  你回去吧
Shrek, no! Wait!
史莱克!等等!
- Let's have a dance then, shall we? - Don't do that!
- 我们跳个舞吧  - 别这样!
Oh, I'm sorry. Do what?
对不起  不要怎样?
- Oh, this? - Yes, that!
- 这样?  - 对  那样
Yes? Yes, do it. Okay.
对?就这样  好
No Shrek!
不  史莱克
- No! Stop it! - You said do it! I'm doin' it.
- 不!停下!  - 你说就这样!我在这样做啊
I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die. Shrek, I'm gonna die.
史莱克  我要死了  我要死了
That'll do, Donkey. That'll do.
这就行了  小驴  这就行了
Cool.
酷
So where is this fire-breathing pain-in-the-neck anyway?
那个喷火的家伙在哪?
Inside, waiting for us to rescue her.
在里面  等我们来救她
I was talkin' about the dragon, Shrek.
我说的是那条龙  史莱克
You afraid?
你怕吗?
No, but...  Shh.
不怕  嘘...
Oh, good. Me neither.
嗯  我也不怕
'Cause there's nothin' wrong with bein' afraid.
害怕并不是过错
Fear's a sensible response to an unfamiliar situation.
害怕是对陌生环境的敏感反应
Unfamiliar dangerous situation, I might add.
陌生的危险环境  我应该说
With a dragon that breathes fire and eats knights and breathes fire,
有一条吃人的会喷火的龙
it sure doesn't mean you're a coward if you're a little scared.
害怕并不意味着你是胆小鬼
I sure as heck ain't no coward. I know that.
我知道史莱克不是胆小鬼
Donkey, two things, okay?
驴  答应我两件事  好吗?
Shut... up.
闭...嘴
Now go over there and see if you can find any stairs.
去那边看看能不能找到楼梯
Stairs? I thought we was lookin' for the princess.
楼梯?我想我们在找公主
The princess will be up the stairs in the highest room in the tallest tower.
公主在最高的塔内最高的房间里
- What makes you think she'll be there? - I read it in a book once.
- 你怎么知道她在那里? - 我从书上看到的
Cool. You handle the dragon. I'll handle the stairs.
酷  你对付龙  我来找楼梯
I'll find those stairs. I'll whip their butt too.
等我找到楼梯  我也要抽它们的屁股
Those stairs won't know which way they're goin'.
楼梯不知道通向哪里
I'm gonna take drastic steps.
我要走难走的路
Kick it to the kerb. Don't mess with me. I'm the stair master.
别打扰我  我是爬楼梯老手
I've mastered the stairs. I wish I had a step right here. I'd step all over it.
我已经占领楼梯了  踏上一步就没有问题了
Well, at least we know where the princess is, but where's the...
至少我们知道公主在哪里  但...
Dragon!
龙!
Donkey, look out!
小驴  当心!
Got ya!
抓住你了!
Oh, what large teeth you have.
你的牙齿真大
I mean, white, sparkling teeth. I know you probably hear this all the time from your food,
我是说  闪亮的牙齿 我知道你经常听到食物这么对你说
but you must bleach, 'cause that is one dazzling smile you got there.
但你一定漂白了  因为笑起来很耀眼
Do I detect a hint of minty freshness?
我闻到了  有薄荷的清香
And you know what else? You're... you're a girl dragon!
你知道吗?  你是条龙姑娘!
Oh, sure! I mean, of course you're a girl dragon.
当然!我是说  当然你是龙姑娘
You're just reeking off feminine beauty.
你身上散发着女性的美
What's the matter with you? You got something in your eye?
你怎么了?眼里掉进东西了?
Man, I'd really love to stay, but, you know, I'm, uh...
我真的愿意留下  但...
I'm an asthmatic, and I don't know if it'd work out if you're gonna blow smoke rings.
我有哮喘病  如果你吐烟圈我会受不了的
Shrek!
史莱克!
No! Shrek! Shrek!
不  史莱克!史莱克!
- WAke up! - What?
- 醒醒!  - 什么?
Are you Princess Fiona?
你是菲奥纳公主吗?
I am, awaiting a knight so bold as to rescue me.
我是  我在等待一个勇敢的骑士来救我
Oh, that's nice. Now let's go!
很好  我们走吧!
But wait, Sir Knight.
等等  骑士先生
This be our first meeting.
这是我们第一次见面
Should it not be a wonderful, romantic moment?
这不是一个非常浪漫的时刻吗?
- Yeah, sorry, lady. There's no time. - Hey, wait. What are you doing?
- 是  对不起  小姐  没时间了 - 等等  你在干什么?
You should sweep me off my feet...
你应该抱起我...
out yonder window and down a rope onto your valiant steed.
跳出窗外落在你的战马上
You've had a lot of time to plan this, haven't you?
你计划这些很长时间了  是吗?
But we have to savour this moment!
但我们应该享受这个时刻!
You could recite an epic poem for me.
你该给我朗诵一段美丽的史诗
A ballad? A sonnet!
小诗?歌谣!
- A limerick? Or something! - I don't think so.
- 五行诗?或是别的! - 我不这样想
Can I at least know the name of my champion?
至少我该知道勇士的名字吧?
Um, Shrek.
我叫史莱克
Sir Shrek.
史莱克先生
I pray that you take this favour as a token of my gratitude.
我祈求你把这个手帕当作我感激的象征
Thanks!
谢谢
You didn't slay the dragon?
你没把龙杀死?
It's on my to-do list. Now come on!
这在我的计划内  快走!
But this isn't right!
不该这样的!
You were meant to charge in, sword drawn, banner flying.
你应该像其他骑士一样  勇往直前
That's what all the other knights did.
所有的骑士都应该这样
Yeah, right before they burst into flame.
是的  在他们被烧成灰烬之前
That's not the point. Oh!
这不是问题所在
Wait. Where are you going? The exit's over there.
你去哪里?出口在那边
Well, I have to save my ass.
我要救我的驴
What kind of knight are you?
你是什么样的骑士?
One of a kind.
独一无二的骑士
Slow down. Slow down, baby, please.
慢点儿  慢点儿  宝贝儿
I believe it's healthy to get to know someone over a long period of time.
时间久了才能全面了解一个人
Just call me old-fashioned.
就叫我老古板吧
I don't want to rush into a physical relationship.
我不想仓促的进一步发展关系
I'm not that emotionally ready for commitment of, uh, this..
我感情上还没准备好这...
Magnitude really is the word I'm looking for.
我在寻找...
Magnitude... Hey, that is unwanted physical contact.
这不需要身体接触
Hey, what are you doing?
你在干什么?
Okay, okay. Let's just back up a little and take this one step at a time.
让我们回头一步一步发展
We really should get to know each other first as friends or pen pals.
我们应该先做个朋友或者笔友
I'm on the road a lot, but I just love receiving cards...
我经常旅行  我喜欢收到明信片...
I'd really love to stay, but...
我真的想留下  但...
Don't do that. That's my tail! That's my personal tail.
别动!这是我私人的尾巴
You're gonna tear it off. I don't give permission What are you gonna do with that?
你要把它去掉?我还没同意
Hey, now. No way. No! No!
现在!不行  不!
No, no! No. No, no, no! No! Oh!
不!不!不!
- Hi, Princess! - It talks!
- 嗨  公主!  - 它会说话!
Yeah, it's getting him to shut up that's the trick.
对  让他闭嘴得有诀窍
Okay, you two, head for the exit!
好  你们俩先走!
I'll take care of the dragon.
我来对付这条龙
Run!
快跑
You did it!
你成功了!你救了我!
You rescued me! You're amizing. You're...
真令人惊叹  你...
You're wonderful. You're...
你太伟大了  你是...
a little unorthodox I'll admit.
我承认你有点儿怪
But thy deed is great, and thine heart is pure.
但你的行为伟大  心地纯洁
I am eternally in your debt.
我会永远感激你
And where would a brave knight be without his noble steed?
没有高贵的马  哪有勇敢的骑士?
I hope you heard that. She called me a noble steed. She think I'm a steed.
我希望你听到了  她说我是高贵的马!
The battle is won.
我们胜利了
You may remove your helmet, good Sir Knight.
你可以摘掉头盔了  骑士先生
- Uh, no. - Why not?
- 不?  - 为什么不?
I have helmet hair.
我...我的头发很乱
Please. I would'st look upon the face of my rescuer.
求求你  我想看看我的救命恩人
No, no, you wouldn't...
不  不  你不想...
But how will you kiss me?
你会吻我吗?
What? That wasn't in the job description.
什么?这不在工作范围内
Maybe it's a perk.
也许这是个奖赏
No. It's destiny. Oh, you must know how it goes.
不  是命运  你一定知道是怎么回事
A princess locked in a tower and beset by a dragon...
一个被关在塔里  由龙看守的公主
is rescue by a brave knight,
被一个勇敢的骑士搭救了
and then they share true love's first kiss.
然后他们分享了真爱的初吻
Hmm? With Shrek? You think... Wait.
和史莱克?  你想...等等
Wait. You think Shrek is your true love?
你以为他是你的真爱?
Well, yes.
是啊!
You think that Shrek is your true love!
你以为史莱克是你的真爱?
What is so funny?
这有什么好笑的?
Let's just say, I'm not your type, okay?
我不是你喜欢的类型
Of course you are. You're my rescuer.
你是的  你救了我
Now...  Now remove your helmet.
现在  摘掉你的头盔
Look. I really don't think this is a good idea.
我想这样不太好
- Just take off the helmet. - I'm not going to.
- 把头盔摘掉吧   - 不
- Take it off! - No!
- 摘掉!  - 不!
- Now! - Okay!
- 立刻!  - 好!
Easy. As you command, Your Highness.
听你的命令  公主殿下
You...  You're a... an ogre.
你...你是个怪物
Oh, you were expecting Prince Charming.
你以为我是个白马王子?
Well, yes, actually.
嗯  对  是这样的
Oh no. This is all wrong.
不  都搞错了
You're not supposed to be an ogre.
你不应该是个怪物的
Princess, I was sent to rescue you by Lord Farquaad, okay?
公主  我是被弗瓜王派来救你的
He's the one who wants to marry you.
是他想跟你结婚
Then why didn't he come to rescue me?
那他为什么不亲自来救我?
Good question. You should ask him that when we get there.
问的好  你应该去那里问他
But I have to be rescued by my true love,
我必须被我的真爱搭救
not by some ogre and his... his pet.
而不该是被怪物和他的宠物搭救
Well so much for noble steed.
再也不是高贵的马了
Look princess. You're not making my job any easier.
你使我的任务更麻烦了
Well I'm sorry, but your job is not my problem.
对不起  你的任务与我无关
You can tell Lord Farquaad that if he wants to rescue me properly,
你去告诉弗瓜王  如果他真的想救我...
I'll be waiting for him right here.
我就在这里等他
Hey, I'm no ones messenger boy, all right? I'm a delivery boy.
嘿  我不负责传信  我只管送你
You wouldn't dare.
你不敢
- Ya comin', Donkey? - Put me down!
- 把我放下!  - 你来吗  小驴?
Yeah, I'm right behind ya.
我在后面跟着你
Put me down or you will suffer the consequences!
放下我  不然你后果自负!
This is not dignified! Put me down!
你太不尊敬我了!放下我!
Okay, so here's another question.
我又有个问题
Say there's a woman that digs you, right, but you don't really like her that way.
有个女人喜欢你  但你不喜欢她
How do you let her down real easy so her feelings aren't hurt,
怎么才能摆脱她而不让她感情受伤害呢?
but you don't get burned to a crisp and eaten?
而你也不会被她所伤害?
You just tell her she's not your true love.
应该告诉她  她不是你的真爱
Everyone knows it what happens when you find your...
当发现你的真爱时  每个人都知道...
The sooner we get to DuLoc the better.
真想一下子赶到杜洛克
Oh, yeah. You're gonna love it there, Princess. It's beautiful!
你会喜欢那里的  公主  那里很美丽!
And what of my groom-to-be? Lord Farquaad? What's he like?
我的未婚夫弗瓜王怎么样? 他长什么样?
Well, let me put it this way, Princess.
这么说吧  公主
Men of Farquaad's stature are in short supply.
像弗瓜王那样身材的人世间少有
I don't know. There are those who think little of him.
不  史莱克  想起他的人都很少
Stop it. Stop it, both of you.
停下  你俩都停下
You know, you're just jealous that you can never measure up to a great ruler like lord Farquaad.
你们只是在嫉妒   你们没法跟伟大的弗瓜王相比
Yeah. Well maybe you're right, Princess.
是  也许你说得对  公主
But I'd let you do the "measuring" when you see him tomorrow.
明天你见到他时  最好亲自量量他
Tomorrow? It's take that long?
明天?要等那么久?
- Shouldn't we stop to make camp? - No, that'll take longer.
- 我们停下露营吧? - 不  那样浪费时间
- We can keep going. - But there are robbers in the woods.
- 我们接着走吧 - 但是森林里可能有强盗
Whoa! Time out, Shrek! Camping's starting to sound good.
停下!露营这个主意不错!
Hey. Come on. I'm scarier than anything we're going to see in this forest.
嘿  我比这个森林里任何东西都可怕
I need to find somewhere to camp now!
我现在要找个地方露营!
- Hey! over here. - Shrek, we can do better than that.
- 嘿!过来! - 史莱克  我们可以找个更好的地方
Now, I don't think this is fit for a princess.
我认为对公主来说并不适合
No, no, it's perfect. It just needs a few homey touches.
不  这很不错   只不过需要一点家的气氛
Homey touches? Like what?
家的气氛?像什么?
A door? Well, gentlemen, I bid thee good night.
一扇门?好吧  绅士们  晚安
Do you want me to come in and read you a bedtime story? 'cause I will.
我临睡前给你讲个故事好吗?我会讲...
I said good night!
我说了  晚安!
Shrek, what are you doing?
史莱克  你要做什么?
I just... You know... Oh, come on.
我只是...你知道...没事的
I was just kidding.
我只是开玩笑
And, uh, that one, that's Throwback,
呃  那个  那是斯洛白克
the only ogre to ever spit over three wheat fields.
是唯一一个能吐过三块麦田的怪物
Right. Yeah.
对  恩
Hey, can you tell my future form these stars?
哎  你能通过星象预言我的未来吗?
Well, the stars don't tell the future, Donkey. They tell stories.
星象不能告诉我们未来   小驴  它会讲故事
Look, there's Bloodnut, the Flatulent.
看  那是布拉纳特臭气
- You can guess what he is famous for. - All right. Now I know you're making this up.
- 你可以猜出为什么它很出名 - 我知道你在瞎编
No. Look. There he is,
不  看  它在那里
and there's the group of hunters running away from his stench.
猎人们都被它熏跑了
Man, there ain't nothin' but a bunch of little dots.
它们只是一群小星星
You know donkey, sometimes things are more than they appear.
有时候事情不像表面看起来那么简单
Forget it.
算了吧
Hey, Shrek, what we gonna do when we get our swamp back, anyway?
嘿  史莱克  我们回到沼泽地之后做什么?
Our swamp?
我们的沼泽?
You know. When we're through rescuing the princess and all that stuff.
你知道  我们救了公主
We? Donkey, there is no "we". There's no "our".
我们?小驴  不是"我们"  没有"我们"
There's just me and my swamp.
那是"我"和"我的沼泽地"
And the first thing I'm gonna do is build a ten-foot wall around my land.
我要做的第一件事就是 在我的领地上建一个十英尺高的围墙
You cut me deep, Shrek.
你伤害了我  史莱克
You cut me real deep just now.
你刚才深深的伤害了我
You know what I think?
你知道我在想什么吗?
I think this whole wall thing is just a way to keep somebody out.
我想围墙只是为了阻挡某些人
- No, do ya think? - Are you hidin' something?
- 不  你这么想?  - 你想藏点东西?
Never mind, Donkey.
别介意  小驴
Oh, this is another one of those onion things, isn't it?
哦  这是另一个洋葱的问题  不是吗?
No, this is one of those drop-it and leave-it-alone things.
不  这是一个不该谈论的事情
- Why don't you want to talk about it? - Why do you want to talk about it?
- 为什么你不想谈这个?  - 为什么你想?
- Oh, Why you block? - I'm not blocking.
- 为什么你要封闭自己?  - 我没有
- Oh yes you are. - Donkey, I'm warning you.
- 哦  你是的   - 小驴  我警告你
- Who are you trying to keep out? Just tell me that Shrek. Who? - Everyone! Okay?
- 你想阻挡谁?  - 所有人!行了吧?
Oh, now we're gettin' somewhere.
哦  我们现在有所进展了
Oh, for 'the love of Pete!
哦  你饶了我吧
Hey, what's your problem Shrek? What do you got against the whole world anyway?
你有什么问题? 你对整个世界有什么不满吗?
Look. I'm not the one with the problem, okay?
不是我有什么不满  好吗?
It's the world that seems to have a problem with me.
是世界对我不满
People take one look at me and go, "Aah! Help! Run!
人们看见我就逃:啊  救命  快跑!
A big, stupid, ugly ogre!"
一个又丑又蠢的怪物
They judge me, before they even know me.
他们不了解我就下了结论
That's why I'm better off alone.
所以我最好单独生活
You know what?
你知道吗?
When we met, I didn't think you're was just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
我遇到你时   我不认为你是一个"又蠢又丑的怪物"
Yeah, I know.
是的  我知道
So, uh, are there any donkeys up there?
呃  天上有驴吗?
Well, there's, um, Gabby,
恩  有  是头多嘴的...
the Small and Annoying.
烦人的小驴
Okay, okay. I see it, now. The big shiny one, right there. That's one there?
哦  我看到了  那个又大又亮的   是那边那个吗?
- That's the moon. - Oh, okay.
- 那是月亮   - 哦
Again. Show me again.
再让我看看
Mirror, mirror, show her to me. Show me the princess.
镜子  镜子  再让我看看公主
Ah. Perfect.
啊  太好了
Mmm, yeah, you know I like it like that.
嗯  你知道  我喜欢这样
- Oh come on, baby. I said I like it. - Donkey, wake up.
- 对  宝贝  我说过我喜欢这样 - 小驴  醒醒
- Huh? What? - Wake up.
- 呃  什么?  - 起床了
- What? - Good morning.
- 什么?   - 早上好
How do you like your eggs?
你喜欢吃什么样的蛋?
- Good morning, Princess! - What's all this about?
- 早上好  公主!  - 这是怎么回事?
You know, we kind of got of to a bad start yesterday.
我们昨天相处的不怎么样
I wanted to make it up to you.
今天我想补偿一下
I mean, after all, you did rescue me.
毕竟  是你救了我
Uh, thanks.
呃  谢谢
Well, eat up. We've got a big day ahead of us.
好吧  快吃  还有很重要的事情呢
Shrek!
史莱克!
What? It's a compliment.
什么?这是赞美
Better out than in, I always say.
我总认为  出去比进去好
Well, it's no way to behave in front of a princess.
在公主面前不要这样
- Thanks - She's as nasty as you are.
- 谢谢  - 她和你一样粗鲁
You know, you're not exactly what I expected.
你知道  你并不清楚我想要什么
Well, maybe you shouldn't judge people before you get to know them.
在了解一个人之前最好不要轻易下结论
Princess!
公主!
What are you doing?
你要干什么?
Be still, mon cherie, for I am your saviour!
别怕  亲爱的  我是你的救星
And I am rescuing you from this green...beast
是我从这个绿...怪物手中救了你
That's my princess! Go find your own!
那是我的公主!去找你自己的!
Please, monster! Can't you see I'm a little busy here?
怪物  你没看见我在忙吗?
Look, pal. I don't know who you think you are!
伙计  你以为你自己是谁!
Oh, of course! How rude that was.
哦  当然!太冒昧了
Please, let me introduce myself.
请让我做个自我介绍
Oh, Merry Men!
哦  伙计们!
I steal from the rich and give to the needy
我劫富济贫
- He takes a wee percentage - But I'm not greedy
- 他只拿了一小部分   - 我并不贪婪
I rescue pretty damsels Man, I'm good
我救了美丽的公主  我是一个好人
What a guy, Monsieur Hood
先生们  跳起来吧
I like an honest fight and a saucy little maid
我喜欢一场公平的决斗和一个可爱的女孩
What he's basically saying is he likes to get... Paid
他想说的是他喜欢...自己应得的
So...When an ogre in the bush grabs a lady by the tush
当一个怪物抓住了一位公主
- That's bad  - That's bad
- 真糟糕   - 真糟糕
When a beauty's with a beast it makes me awfully mad
当我想到美女与野兽一起  就使我恼怒
He's mad He's really, really mad
他发怒了  他真的发怒了
I'll take my blade and ram it through your heart
我要将我的剑插入你的心脏
Keep your eyes on me, boys 'cause I'm about to start
看着我  因为我要开始了
Man, that was annoying!
这些家伙真烦人!
Oh, you little...
哦  你这个小...
Um, shall we?
呃  我们可以走了吗?
Hold the phone.
等一下
Oh! Whoa!, whoa, whoa. Hold on now.
哦  先等等
- Where did that come from? - What?
- 你从哪里学来的?   - 什么?
That! Back there. That was amazing!
那个!就是刚才那个  真令人惊奇!
Where did you learn that?
你从哪里学来的?
Well-When one lives alone,
一个人自己住的时候
uh, one has to learn these things in case there's a...
就应该学一些东西来以防万一...
- There is an arrow in your butt! - What?
- 你屁股上有根箭!  - 什么?
- What? Oh, would you look at that? - Oh, no. This is all my fault.
- 哦  真的吗?  - 噢  不  这都是我不好
- I'm so sorry.  - Why? What's wrong?
- 对不起   - 为什么?怎么了?
- Shrek's hurt. - Shrek's hurt. Shrek's hurt? Oh, no, Shrek's gonna die.
- 史莱克受伤了 - 史莱克受伤了  他受伤了?哦  不  他要死了
- Donkey, I'm okay. - You can't do this to me Shrek. I'm too young for you to die.
- 小驴  我没事 - 你不能死  我还很小  你不能死
Keep your legs elevated. Turn your head and cough.
把你的脚抬起来  转过你的头咳嗽
- Does anyone know how the Heimlich? - Donkey! Calm down.
- 有人会海姆利克疗法吗? - 镇静点  小驴
If you want to help Shrek, run into the woods and find me a blue flower with red thorns.
如果你想救史莱克 快去森林里找一朵蓝色的花  花上有红色的刺
Blue flower, red thorns. Okay, I'm on it. Blue flower, red thorns.
蓝色的花  红色的刺 好的  我就去  蓝色的花  红色的刺
Don't die Shrek. And if you see a long tunnel, stay away from the light!
不要死  史莱克 如果你看到一条长隧道  远离光线
- Donkey! - Oh, yeah. Right. Blue Flower, red thorns.
- 小驴!  - 好的  蓝色的花  红色的刺
- Blue flower, red thorns. - What are the flowers for?
- 蓝色的花  红色的刺  - 那花儿有什么用?
- For getting rid of the Donkey. - Ah.
- 是为了让驴走开  - 哦
Now you hold still, and I'll yank this thing out.
现在你先别动  我要把刺一下拔出来
Ow! Hey! Easy with the yankin'.
喔!轻点
- I'm sorry, but it has to come out. - No, it's tender.
- 抱歉  但一定要拔出来  - 不  轻点儿
Now, hold on.
现在  坚持住
- What you're doing here is the opposite of help. - Don't move.
- 没什么用  - 别动
- Look, time out. - Would you...
- 停下  - 你能...
Okay. What do you propose we do?
好的  你希望我怎么做?
Blue flower, red thorns. Blue flower, red thorns. Blue flower, red thorns.
蓝色的花  红色的刺 蓝色的花  红色的刺
This would be so much easier if I wasn't colour-blind!
如果我不是色盲的话就容易多了
Blue flower, red thorns
蓝色的花  红色的刺
Hold on, Shrek! I'm comin'!
坚持住  史莱克!我来了!
Ow! Not good.
太痛了
Okay. Okay, I can nearly see the head.
好的  好的  马上就好
It's just about...
就要...
Nothing happened. We were just
没什么  我们正准备...
Look, if you wanted to be alone, all you had to do is ask.
如果你不希望有人打搅 只要说一声就可以了
Oh, come on! That's the last thing on my mind.
哦  别傻了  这不是我想要的事情
The princess here was just...
公主正要...
Hey, what's that?
嘿!那是什么?
That's... Is that blood?
那是...血吗?
My beloved monster and me
我的怪物爱人和我
We go everywhere together
我们一起去任何地方
Wearin' a raincoat that has four sleeves
一起穿一件有四条袖子的雨衣
Gets us through all kinds of weather
不管什么天气都一起渡过
She will always be the only thing
她永远是我的唯一
That comes between me and the awful sting
是在我和糟糕的事情之间
That comes from living in a world that's so damn mean
这是我生命的意义  这是一个严肃的话题
There it is, Princess.
就是这里  公主
Your future awaits you.
你的未来在等你
- That's Duloc? - Yeah, I know.
- 那是杜洛克吗?  - 是的  我知道
You know, Shrek thinks Lord Farquaad's compensating for something,
你知道  史莱克认为弗瓜王在弥补什么
which I think means, he has a really...
我想说的是他有一个...
Um, I, uh...
呃  我  呃...
- I guess we better move on. - Sure.
- 我们还是上路吧  - 好的
But Shrek?
但是  史莱克?
I'm...  I'm worried about Donkey.
我...  我很担心小驴
- What? - I mean, look at him.
- 什么?  - 我说  你看他
- He doesn't look so good. - What are you talking about? I'm fine.
- 他看起来不太好  - 你在说什么?我很好
Well, that's what they always say, and the next thing you know, you're on your back.
他们总是这么说  然后他们就倒下了
- Dead. - You know, she's right.
- 死去  - 你知道  她说的对
You look awful. Do you want to sit down?
你看起来气色不好  你想坐下休息一会吗?
- You know, I'll make you up some tea. - Well, I didn't want to say nothing
- 给你弄杯茶  - 我原来不想说
but I've got this twinge in my neck, and when I turn my head like this, look.
我的脖子很疼  而且我要是像这样转头  瞧
Ow! See?
哦!看见了?
- Who's hungry? I'll find us some dinner. - I'll get the firewood.
- 谁饿了吗?我要去找点吃的  - 我去捡柴火
Hey, where are you goin'? Oh man, I can't feel my toes!
你去哪?伙计  我的脚趾没有知觉了!
I don't have any toes!
我没有知觉了!
I think I need a hug.
我需要一个拥抱
Mmm. This is good. This is really good.
嗯  很好吃  真的很好吃
- What is this? - Uh, weedrat.
- 这是什么?  - 田鼠
Rotisserie style.
是烤的
No kidding.
别开玩笑了
Well, this is delicious.
真的  很美味
Well, they're also great in stews.
炖着吃也很香
Now, I don't mean to brag, but I make a mean wheedrat stew.
我不是说大话  我弄的炖田鼠很棒
I guess I'll be dining a little differently tomorrow night.
我想明天的晚餐应该会有点不同吧
Maybe you can come visit me in the swamp sometime.
以后你可以来沼泽看我
I'll cook all kinds of stuff for you.
我会给你做很多好吃的
Swamp toast soup, fish eye tartare... you name it.
沼泽蛤蟆汤  鱼眼油饼...你随便点
I'd like that.
我想我会喜欢的
See the pyramids along the Nile
去看埃及的金字塔
Um, Princess?
呃  公主?
- Watch the sunrise from a tropic isle  - -Yes, Shrek?
- 在岛上看日出  - 史莱克
- I was wondering - ust remember, darling all the while
- 我  我想问...  - 记住每一个瞬间
Are, you...
你...
You belong to me
你属于我
Are you gonna eat that?
你还吃吗?
- Man, isn't this romantic? Just look at that sunset. - Sunset?
- 伙计  很浪漫  不是吗?去看日落吧  - 日落?
Oh, no! I mean, it's late.
哦  不!我的意思是  太晚了
- I...  It's very late. - What?
- 我...太晚了  - 什么?
Wait a minute. I see what's goin' on here.
等一下  我明白是怎么回事了
- You're afraid of the dark, aren't you? - Yes!
- 你害怕黑夜  是吗?  - 是的!
Yes, that's it. I'm terrified. You know I'd better go inside.
是的  是这样  我害怕  我最好进去
But don't feel bad, Princess. I used to be afraid of the dark, too, until...
别怕  公主  我以前也怕黑  直到...
Hey, no, wait. I'm still afraid of the dark.
不  等等  我还是怕黑
Good night.
晚安
I really see what's going on
现在我明白发生了什么
Oh, what are you talkin' about?
你明白什么?
I don't even wanna hear it. Look, I'm an animal, and I got instincts.
我什么也没有听见   但是我有动物的直觉
I know that you two are diggin' on each other. I could feel it.
我知道   你们互相都有好感  我能感觉的到
Oh, you're crazy. I'm just bringing her back to Farquaad.
你乱讲  我只是把她送到弗瓜王那儿
Oh, come on, Shrek. Wake up and smell the pheromones.
拜托  史莱克  抓住机会
Just go in and tell her how you feel
去跟她表白吧
There's nothing to tell. Besides, even if I did tell her that,
没什么好说的  还有  即使我去跟她...
well you know...
你知道...
and I'm not sayin' that I do 'cause I don't...
我不会去的  因为...
she's a princess and I'm...
她是一位公主  而我是...
An ogre?
一个怪物?
Yeah. An ogre.
是的  一个怪物
- Hey, where are you goin'? - To get... more firewood.
- 嘿  你去哪里?  - 去找些...柴火
Princess?
公主
Princess Fiona?
菲奥娜公主
Princess, where are you?
公主  你在哪里?
Princess?
公主?
It's very spooky in here. I ain't playing no games.
这里有点怪异  我可不是在玩游戏
- Oh, no! - No, help!
- 哦  不!  - 不  救命!
- Shh! - Shrek! Shrek! Shrek! - No, it's okay. It's okay.
- 嘘! - 史莱克  史莱克  史莱克 - 不  没什么事了  没事了
- What did you do with the princess? - Donkey, shhh, I'm the princess.
- 公主在哪里?  - 小驴  我就是公主
It's me, in this body.
这是我的身体
Oh, my God! You ate the princess!
哦  我的上帝!你吃了公主
- Can you hear me? - Donkey!
- 你能听到我吗?  - 小驴
- Listen, keep breathing! I'll get you out of there! - No!
- 听着  坚持住!我会把你弄出来的 - 不!
- Shrek! Shrek! Shrek! - Shh.
- 史莱克  史莱克  史莱克   - 嘘
- Shrek! - This is me.
- 史莱克  - 是我
Princess?
公主?
What happened to you? You're, uh, uh,
发生什么事了?你怎么...
uh, different.
变样了
- I'm ugly, okay? - Well, yeah!
- 我变丑了  是吗?  - 哦  是的
Was it something that you ate? 'Cause I told Shrek those rats was a bad idea.
是因为你吃的东西吗? 我告诉过史莱克吃老鼠不好
- You are what you eat, I said. Now... - No.
- 我说是因为你吃的东西...  - 不
I... I've been this way as long as I can remember.
我...我从记事起就这个样了
What do you mean? Look, I ain't never seen you like this before.
什么意思?我从未见过你这个样子
It only happens when the sun goes down.
只有日落后才会变成这样
"By night one way, by day another.
白天一个样  晚上一个样
"This shall be the norm...
形成了规律
"until you find true love's first kiss...
只有得到真爱的初吻
and then, take love's true form. "
然后变成他的模样
Ah, that's beautiful. I didn't know you wrote poetry.
啊  真美  我还不知道你会写诗
It's a spell.
这是个诅咒
When I was a little girl,
我小的时候
a witch cast a spell on me.
一个巫婆诅咒了我
Every night I become this.
每天晚上我就会变成这个样
This horrible, ugly beast!
一个可怕而又丑陋的怪物
I was placed in a tower to await the day my true love would rescue me.
我被困在城堡中  等待真爱来救我
That's why I have to marry lord Farquaad tomorrow...
这就是为什么我必须在 明天日落前跟弗瓜王结婚
before the sun sets and he sees me...
在他见到我这样子以前
like this.
像这样
All right, all right. Calm down. Look, it's not that bad.
好的  冷静点  看  这不是很坏
You're not that ugly. Well, I ain't gonna lie. You are ugly.
你不是很丑  我不会撒谎  你是丑
But you only look like this at night. Shrek's ugly 24-7.
但你只是夜晚丑  史莱克却时刻如此
But Donkey, I'm a princess,
但是  小驴  我是一位公主
and this is not how a princess is meant to look.
这不是一位公主该有的长相
Princess, how 'bout if you don't marry Farquaad?
公主  你不跟弗瓜王结婚怎么样?
I have to.
我必须这样
Only my true love's kiss can brake the spell.
只有真爱的人的吻才能解除诅咒
But you know, you're kind of an ogre,
但是  你是一个善良的怪物
and Shrek...  well, you've got a lot in common.
而且  史莱克  你们有很多共同点
Shrek?
史莱克?
Princess, I... Uh, how's it going, first of all?
公主  我...你好吗?
Good? Um, good for me too.
好?我很好
I'm okay.
我也很好
I saw this flower and thought of you because it's pretty and...
我看到这些花想到你  因为花很漂亮...
well, I don't really like it, but I thought you may like it, 'cause you're pretty.
我不怎么喜欢  但是我想你会喜欢   因为你很漂亮
But I like you anyway. I'd...
反正我很喜欢你  我...
I'm in trouble. Okay, here we go.
对我来说很难  好的  走吧
I can't just marry whoever I want.
我不能随便嫁人的
Take a good look at me, Donkey.
看着我  小驴
I mean, really,
我说的是真的
who could ever love a beast so hideous and hugly?
谁会爱上一个丑陋的怪物?
"Princess" and "ugly" don't go together.
公主和丑八怪不能在一起
That's why I can't stay here with Shrek.
这就是我不能跟史莱克在一起的原因
My only chance to live happily ever after is to marry my true love.
我唯一的机会就是嫁给真爱的人
Don't you see, Donkey?
你明白吗  小驴?
That's just how it has to be.
我必须这么做
It's the only way to break the spell.
这是解除诅咒的唯一办法
- You at least gotta tell Shrek the truth. - No!
- 你至少应该告诉史莱克真相  - 不!
You can't breathe the word. No one must ever know.
你一个字也不能说   没有人知道这个秘密
What's the point of being able to talk if you gotta keep secrets?
如果要保密为什么要告诉我?
Promise you won't tell. Promise!
答应我保密  发誓
All right, all right. I won't tell him. But you should.
好的  好的  我不会告诉他 但你可以告诉他
I just know, before this is over, I'm gonna need a whole lot of serious therapy.
在这些结束之前  我需要接受治疗
Look at my eye twitchin'.
瞧  我的眼睛在抽搐
I tell him, I tell him not.
告诉他  不告诉他
I tell him.
告诉他
Shrek!
史莱克!
Shrek, there's something I want...
史莱克  有些事  我想...
Shrek.
史莱克
- Are you all right? - Perfect!
- 你还好吗?  - 我很好!
Never been better.
好的不得了
I... I don't...  There's something I have to tell you.
我...我不...我有些事情要告诉你
You don't have to tell me anything, Princess.
你不必告诉我任何事情  公主
- I heard enough last night. - You heard what I said?
- 我昨晚听够了 - 什么  你听见我说的话了?
Every word.
每一句
I thought you'd understand?
我想你能理解
Oh, I understand!
我理解
Like you said, "Who could love a hideous, ugly beast?"
就像你说的  谁会爱上一个丑陋的怪物?
But I thought that wouldn't matter to you.
但我以为这对你来说无所谓
Yeah, well, it does.
是吗?无所谓
Ah, right on time.
啊  真准时
Princess, I brought you a little something.
公主  我给你带来个小东西
What'd I miss? What'd I miss?
我错过了什么吗?我错过了什么吗?
Who said that? Couldn't have been a donkey.
是谁说的?不可能是驴
Princess Fiona.
菲奥娜公主
As promised. Now hand it over.
完成你的承诺
Very well, ogre. The deed to your swamp, cleared out as agreed.
好的  怪物  你的沼泽地的契约
Take it and go before I change my mind.
在我改变主意之前拿走吧
Forgive me, Princess, for startling you,
原谅我  公主  让你吃惊了
but you startled me,
但是你也让我吃惊了
For I've never seen such a radiant beauty before.
我从没有见过这样的美人
I am lord Farquaad.
我是弗瓜王
Lord Farquaad? Oh, no, no.
弗瓜王?哦  不  不
Forgive me, my lord, for I was just saying...
请原谅我  我正要...
a short... farewell.
告别
That is so sweet. You don't have to raise good manners on the ogre.
真善良  你不必对那个怪物那么客气
It's not like it has feelings.
它没有感情
No. You're right. It doesn't.
你是对的  它没有
Princess Fiona, beautiful fair flawless Fiona.
菲奥娜公主  美丽  完美无暇的公主
I ask your hand in marriage.
我向你求婚
Will you be the perfect bride for the perfect groom?
你愿意成为完美新郎的完美新娘吗?
Lord Farquaad, I accept. Nothing would make...
弗瓜王  我愿意  没有什么...
Excellent! I'll start the plans for tomorrow we wed!
太好了  我决定  我们明天就举行婚礼!
No! I mean, uh,
不  我是说...
Why wait?
为什么要等明天?
Let's get married today before the sun sets.
让我们在今天日落以前就结婚
Oh, anxious, are we? You're right.
哦  着急了  是吧?你说的对
The sooner, the better. There's so much to do!
越快越好  有很多事情要做
There is the caterer, the cake, the band, the guest list.
宴会  蛋糕  乐队  客人名单
Captain, round up some guests.
队长  快去请客人!
Fare-thee-well, ogre.
再见了  怪物
Shrek, what are you doing? You let her get away.
史莱克  你在干什么?你就这样让她走了?
- Yeah? So what? - Shrek, there's something about her you don't know.
- 是吗?那又怎么样? - 史莱克  有些事你应该知道
Look, I talked to her last night. She's
我昨晚跟她谈话  她是...
Yeah I know you talked to her last night. You're great pals, aren't ya?
我知道你跟她昨晚谈话   你们是好朋友  不是吗?
Now, if you two are such good friends, why didn't you follow her home?
你俩那么好  你为什么不跟着她走?
Shrek, I wanna go with you.
史莱克  我想跟着你
I told you, didn't I? You're not coming home with me.
我没告诉过你吗?你不能跟我回家
I live alone! My swamp! Me! Nobody else!
我单独生活!我的沼泽!我!没有别人!
Understand? Nobody!
明白吗?没有别人!
Especially useless, pathetic, annoying, talking donkeys!
特别是无用的  可怜的  烦人的会说话的驴
- But. I thought...  - Yeah. You know what?
- 但是  我想...  - 你知道什么?
You thought wrong!
你的想法错了
Shrek.
史莱克
Donkey?
小驴?
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
I would think, of all the people, you would recognize a wall when you see one.
我想  对每一个人  你要学会认识墙
Well, yeah.
对
But the wall's supposed to go around my swamp, not through it.
但是墙应该围绕着我的沼泽  而不是穿过
It is around your half. See, that's your half, and this is my half.
是这样的  这是你的一半  那是我的一半
Oh, your half? Hmm.
哦  你的一半
Yes, my half. I helped rescue the princess.
对  我的一半  我帮你救了公主
I did half the work, I get half the booty.
我做了一半的工作  我应该得到一半的奖品
Now hand me that big old rock, the one that looks like your head.
现在把那个大石头给我   就是像你脑袋的那个
- Back off! - No, you back off.
- 退后!  - 不  你退后
- This is my swamp! - Our swamp.
- 这是我的沼泽  - 我的
- Let go, Donkey! - You let go.
- 放开  小驴!  - 不  你放开
- Stubborn jackass! - Smelly ogre.
- 顽固的驴!  - 臭怪物!
Fine!
好吧!
- Hey, hey, come back here. I'm not through with you yet. - Well, I'm through with you.
- 回来  我还没有说完 - 但是我已经跟你说完了
Uh...uh. Well, you know, with you it's always, "Me, me, me!"
跟你在一起  你总是"我  我  我"
Well, guess what! Now it's my turn!
猜猜看!该我了!
So you just shut up and pay attention!
闭嘴  听我说!
You are mean to me.
你对我总是很刻薄
You insult me and you don't appreciate anything that I do!
你侮辱我而且你不感激我做的每件事
You're always pushing me around or pushing me away.
你总是把我呼来喝去
Oh, yeah? Well, if I treated you so bad, how come you came back?
是吗   如果我对你这么不好  为什么你还要回来?
Because that's what friend do! They forgive each other!
因为我们是朋友  朋友会原谅彼此的
Oh, yeah. You're right, Donkey.
哦  你说的对  小驴
I forgive you... for stabbin' me in the back!
我原谅你背叛了我
Ohh! You're so wrapped up in layers, onion boy, you're afraid of your own feelings.
你把自己裹在层里  洋葱仔  你害怕你自己的感觉
- Go away! - There you are, doing it again just like you did to Fiona.
- 走开!  - 你又那么做了
And all she ever do was like you, maybe even love you.
就像对公主一样  她喜欢你  甚至爱上你
Love me? She said I was ugly, a hideous creature.
爱上我?她说我是一个丑陋可怕的怪物
I heard the two of youtalking.
我听见你们俩的谈话了
She wasn't talking about you.
她不是说你
She was talking about, uh, somebody else.
她是在说...别人
She wasn't talking about me?
她不是说我?
Well, then who was she talking about?
那她说的是谁?
Uh...uh, no way. I ain't saying anything. You don't wanna listen to me.
我什么都不说  反正你也没有兴趣听
- Right? Right? - Donkey!
- 是吗?是吗?  - 小驴!
No!
不!
Okay, look. I'm sorry, all right?
好  我道歉  好吗?
I'm sorry.
对不起
I guess I am just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
我是一个愚蠢而又丑陋的怪物
Can you forgive me?
你能原谅我吗?
Hey, that's the friends are for, right?
朋友就是这样的嘛  对吗?
Right. Friends?
正确  朋友?
Friends.
朋友
So, um,
那么...
what did Fiona say about me?
公主是怎么说我的
What are you asking me for? Why don't you just go ask her?
为什么问我?你应该去问她
The wedding! We'll never make it in time.
婚礼!我们来不及了
Never fear, for where there's a will, there's a way.
别急  有志者事竟成
And I have a way.
我有办法
Donkey?
小驴
I guess this is just my animal magnetism.
我想这是我个人的魅力
Aw, come here, you.
你  过来
All right, all right. Don't get all slobbery. No one likes a kiss ass.
别这样  没人喜欢拍驴屁的
All right, hop on and hold on tight.
好  上来  抓紧
I hadn't have a chance to install seat belts yet.
我还没来得及装安全带呢
People of DuLoc,
杜洛克的公民们
we gather here today...
我们今天到这来
to bear witness...
来见证...
to the union...
结合...
- of our new king  - Excuse me.
- 为我们的新国王   - 打扰一下
Could we just skip ahead to the "I do's"?
我们能不能直接跳到"我愿意"?
Go on.
继续
Go ahead, have some fun. If we need you, I'll whisle. How about that?
走找点乐子  需要你时我会吹口哨的
Shrek, wait, wait! Wait a minute!
史莱克  等等  等等!
- You want to do this right, don't you? - What are you talking about?
- 你要那么做  是吗?  - 你在说什么?
There's a line, There's a line you gotta wait for.
你必须等一句台词
The preacher's gonna say, "Speak now or forever hold your peace. "
等待牧师说  现在说否则永远保持沉默
- That's when you say, "I object!" - I don't have time for this!
- 这时你说  我反对   - 我没有时间听这些
Wait, wait. What are you doing? Listen to me!
等等  你听我说
- Look, you love this woman, don't you? - Yes.
- 你爱那个女人吗?  - 是的
- You wanna hold her? - Yes.
- 你想牵她的手  对吗?  - 是的
- Please her? - Yes!
- 让她高兴?  - 是的
Then you got to, got to try a little tenderness
那你就要去...去...试着温柔点
- The chicks love that romantic crap! - All right! Cut it out.
- 女人都喜欢这种浪漫的废话! - 是的  完全正确
- When does this guy say the line? - We gotta check it out.
- 那家伙什么时候说这个? - 我们得查一下
And so, by the power vested in me,
以我的权力
- What do you see? - The whole town's in there.
- 你看见什么了?  - 全城的人都在
- I know pronounce you husband and wife, - They're at the altar.
- 我宣布你们为夫妻  - 他们在祭坛上
- king and queen. - Mother Fletcher! He already said it.
- 国王和王后  - 他已经说了
for the love of Pete!
看在圣彼得的面上
I object!
我反对!
Shrek?
史莱克?
Oh, now what does he want?
他想干什么?
Hi, everyone. Havin' a good time, are ya?
各位  过得很愉快  是吗?
I love DuLoc, first of all.
首先我很喜欢杜洛克
- Very clean. - What are you doing here?
- 很干净  - 你来这里干什么?
Really, it's rude enough being alive when no one wants you.
没有人欢迎你来
- But showing up uninvited to a wedding - Fiona!
- 你不请自来太无礼了   - 菲奥纳
- I need to talk to you. - Oh, now you wanna talk?
- 我想跟你谈谈  - 你想说什么?
Well, it's a little late for that, so if you'll excuse me...
现在说有点晚了  但如果你能原谅我...
- But you can't marry him. - And why not?
- 你不能嫁给他  - 为什么?
Because... Because he's just marrying you so he can be king.
因为...因为他娶你只是为了能当上国王
Outrageous! Fiona, don't listen to him.
可恶!菲奥纳  别听他的
- He's not your true love. - And what do you know about true love?
- 他不是你的真爱  - 你懂什么是真爱吗?
Well, I... Uh...
嗯  我  我...
- I mean... - Oh, this is precious.
- 我是说...   - 真有意思
the ogre has fallen in love with the princess!
这个怪物爱上了公主!
Oh, good Lord.
哦  上帝啊
An ogre and a princess!
一个怪物和一个公主
Shrek, is this true?
史莱克  这是真的吗?
Who cares? It's preposterous!
谁关心呢?真荒谬!
Fiona, my love, we're but a kiss away for our "happily ever after. "
菲奥纳  我的爱人   吻完我们就能得到永远的幸福
Now kiss me! Mmmm!
吻我!
"By night one way, by day another. "
白天一个样  晚上一个样
I wanted to show you before.
我想给你看我晚上的样子
that explains a lot.
我明白了
Ugh! It's disgusting!
真恶心
Guards! Guards!
卫兵  卫兵
I order you to get that out of my sight now! Get them!
我命令你们把他们赶走
- Get them both! - No, no!
- 把他们俩都赶走  - 不  不
This hocus-pocus alters nothing. This marriage is binding, and that makes me king!
这不会改变任何事情   这婚姻仍然有效  我成为了国王
- See? See? - No, let go of me! Shrek!
- 瞧  瞧  - 不  放开我  史莱克!
No! Don't just stand there, you morons.
不!别光站在那里  一群笨蛋
Get out of my way! Fiona!
滚开!菲奥纳!
I'll make you regret the day we met. I'll see you drawn and quartered!
我要让你后悔和我见面   我要让你受尽折磨
- You'll beg for death to save you! - No! Shrek!
- 到时候你会求我杀了你  - 不  史莱克!
- And as for you, my wife. - Fiona!
- 至于你  我的妻子  - 菲奥纳!
I'll have you locked back in that tower for the rest of your days!
我会把你锁到城堡里渡过你的余生
I am king!
我是国王
I will have order! I will have perfection! I will have...
我有权力  我至高无上  我将有...
- Aah! - All right. Nobody move.
- 好  - 大家都别动
I got a dragon here, and I'm not afraid to use it.
我有一条龙  而且会毫不犹豫的使用
I'm a donkey on the edge!
我是头发怒的驴
Celebrity marriages. They never last, do they?
名人的婚姻都没有长久的  对吗?
Go ahead Shrek.
去吧  史莱克
Uh, Fiona?
呃  菲奥纳
Yes, Shrek?
是的  史莱克
I... I love you.
我...我爱你
Really?
真的吗?
Really, really.
真的  真的
I love you too.
我也爱你
"Until you find true love's first kiss...
直到你找到真爱并得到他的吻
and then take love's true form. "
然后变成他的模样
"Take love's true form. Take love's true form. "
变成他的模样  变成他的模样
Fiona?
菲奥纳
Fiona.
Are you all right?
你还好吗?
Well, yes.
是的  很好
But I don't understand.
但我不明白
I'm supposed to be beautiful.
我想应该变美的
But you are beautiful.
你很漂亮
I was hoping this would be a happy ending.
我希望是一个幸福的结局
I thought love was only true in fairy tales
我想爱情是童话故事中唯一真实的东西
Meant for someone else but not for me
对别人有意义  但是对我没有
Love was out to get me
爱情不会光顾我
That's the way it seemed
好像一直是这样
Disappointment haunted all my dreams
失望袭击着我的梦想
And then I saw her face
但是当我看到她的脸
Now I'm a believer
现在我是一个信徒
And not a trace Of doubt in my mind
不再怀疑是个踪迹
I'm in love
我恋爱了
I'm a believer I couldn't leave her
我是一个信徒  我离不开她
If I tried
如果我试了
God bless us, every one.
神会保佑我们每一个人
- Come on  - Then I saw her face
- 一起来吧  - 当我看见她的脸
Now I'm a believer
现在我是一个信徒
Not a trace
不是踪迹
Of doubt in my mind
从不怀疑
I'm in love
我恋爱了
I'm a believer I couldn't leave her if I tried
我是个信徒
Then I saw her face
当我看见她的脸
Now I'm a believer
我是一个信徒
Not a trace
不是踪迹
Of doubt in my mind
从不怀疑  再来一次
I'm in love I'm a believer
我恋爱了
Come on!
大家一起来
I believe, I believe I believe, I believe
我相信  我相信  我相信  我相信
I believe, I believe I believe, I believe, I believe, hey
我相信  我相信  我相信  我相信  我相信
Y'all sing it with me!
跟我一起唱
Believe
我相信
I believe
I'm a believer
我相信
I believe
Oh, that's funny. Oh. Oh.
哦  真有趣
I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
我不能呼吸  我不能呼吸了
I believe in self-assertion
我相信自我感觉
Destiny or a slight divertion
命运有时会改变
Now it seems I've got my head on straight
现在好像青睐我了
I'm freak an apparition
我是一个丑八怪  一个怪物